Register of the Charles Luther Boynton Papers, 1901-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Luther Boynton Papers,
1901-1967
XX284
Boynton, Charles Luther, 1881-
11 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes. (4.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, diaries, writings, pamphlets, and photographs, relating to missionary work in Shanghai, the Shanghai American School, and social conditions in China.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Related Materials
Charles and Edmund Boynton papers. Special Collections, Honnold/Mudd Library, Claremont University Consortium.
Access Points
Missions--China.; China.; China--Description and travel.; Shanghai (China); Missionaries.
Biographical Note
1881, June 8 Born, Townshend, Vermont
1901 Graduated, Pomona College
1901-1903 Assistant Secretary, State Committee YMCAs of Kansas
1903-1906 Business Secretary, Student Department, International Committee YMCA, New York
1906-1914 Business Secretary, National Committee YMCAs of China
1907 Attended Centenary Conference, New York
1908, June 8 Married Leila Dozier
1909-1920 Member, original Board of Managers of the Shanghai American School, which he founded
1914-1915 Foreign Missions Conference of North America Editor, The Missions Code
1915-1920 Business and Statistical Secretary of China Continuation Committee
1915-1923 Served with U.S. Army, Shanghai Volunteer Corps
1920-1922 Business Manager, Shanghai American School; Executive Secretary, 1922-1923; Acting Principal, 1923-1924; Principal, 1924-1926
1927-1947 Business Secretary of National Christian Council of China; Acting General Secretary, 1941; Honorary Secretary, 1947-1950 Compiled the handbook The Christian Movement in China
1943-1945 Interned at Chapei Civil Assembly Center during the Japanese occupation of Shanghai
1946 Returned to the United States
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1905-1967. (Box 1)
  Announcements, correspondence, invitations, memorabilia, receipts, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Biographical data
  - Clippings
  - Correspondence with the University of Oregon, Eugene
  - National Christian Council of China - Resolution on the Services of Charles Luther Boynton (hereafter CLB)
  - Notes and indexes of Boynton Papers
  - Receipts
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1901-1967. (Box 1-2)
  Arranged in three groups: general correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent; open letters sent annually to his friends entitled Dear Friends, arranged chronologically; and personal correspondence with his family, arranged chronologically. See also SUBJECT FILE, Post World War II; CHAPEI CIVIL ASSEMBLY CENTER; SHANGHAI AMERICAN SCHOOL
  - General correspondence (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified
    - Boynton, Edmund C. See also SUBJECT FILE, Post World War II
    - Boynton, Leila Dozier. See also CHAPEI CIVIL ASSEMBLY CENTER
    - Bramble, Joan and Ronald
    - Davis, Lowry and Mary B.
    - Fahs, Charles H.
    - Farrior, Stacy and Kitty
    - Fickett, Nellie
    - Field, Gertrude
    - First Federal Savings Alhambra, A.G. Kruse
    - Fisher, A.J. and Dorothy
    - Fitch, Mr. and Mrs. George A.
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson
    - Fox, George A.
    - Fridell, Elmer A.
    - Fulcher, Helen McCracken
    - Hening, S.E.
    - Ho, T.K. (Deputy Mayor of Shanghai)
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Philip T. McLean
    - Kerr, Willis
    - Magill, Orrin R., Jr.
    - Marriage License Bureau, Los Angeles, Ella Moody
    - Patch, George E. and Julia
    - Rawbinson, John L.
    - Renwick, William G.
    - Turner, Eugene A.
    - U.S. State Department
    - Westbrook, Louise and Hart
  - Dear friends open letters
    - 1909
    - 1929-1957
      - Original copies
      - Printed copies
  - Personal and family correspondence (Box 2)
    - Kansas
      - August 1901-January 1903. Transcribed letters to his mother
      - July 1902-June 1903. Original letters to his mother, father and brother
    - New York
      - July 1903-July 1904
      - June 1904-July 1905
      - August 1905-October 1906
    - Early years in China, 1906-1909
    - Transcripts of postcards, 1903-1953
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1901-1963. (Box 3)
  Addresses, autobiographical writings, drafts, notes, personal meditations, reports, sermons, arranged alphabetically by title
  - American Missions in China, n.d. Two carbon copies of an essay on the nineteenth century movement (Box 3)
  - Appeal to the Community Church of Shanghai, 16 June 1940. Typescript of an address requesting aid for the Hopei and Shantung Provinces
  - Attempting the Impossible, 9 August 1936. Typescript and carbon fragments of a speech
  - Autobiographical writings. See also Shanghai American School, The Growth of an Idea
    - General. Carbon typescript of notes and portions of an autobiographical article
    - How War Came to Shanghai, August 1937. Transcribed letter to E.C. Lobenstine
    - Kansas travel diary, 1901-1903. Typewritten transcript of the original
    - Notes on Life in the Chapei Civil Assembly Center, 1943-1945. Carbon typescript, copied from original books
    - Peace, Peace, When there is No Peace, 29 May 1963. Typescript concerning Shanghai after 1941.
    - Shanghai American School History, n.d. Typescript and carbon copy
    - Since Pearl Harbor, n.d. Typescript and carbon copy of a description of life and work at Chapei
    - Thirty-Nine Years (1906-1946). Typescript of a description of life and work in China
    - This, I Believe, 7 May 1906. Carbon copies of CLB's statement of faith upon ordination, prefaced with an autobiographical sketch. See also Statement of Faith for original text
  - Broadcast of the American Red Cross, May 1938. Typescript of a speech written for Norman Davis, President of the American Red Cross
  - Chapei Civil Assembly Speeches, 19 October 1944 - 15 April 1945. Handwritten church services and sermons
  - Is the Church in China Declining? December 1932. Printed copy of an article published in The Chinese Recorder
  - Lea, General Homer, ca. 1951. Typescript of CLB's memorandum of his contacts with Lea
  - The Life Eternal, 13 March 1938. Printed copy of a sermon delivered at the Community Church of Shanghai
  - Memorial Day Address at Bubbling Well Cemetary, 1924. Typescript of an address to the Shanghai American Community, the Shanghai American School, and the American Company of the Shanghai Volunteer Corps
  - Nominating Speech for H.F. Kay, Spring 1945. Typescript of a speech recommending Kay as American representative of the Chapei Civil Assembly Center
  - Notes for addresses, sermons, etc, 1906-1941. Typescripts
  - Our Christianity and our Staff, ca. 1930. Typescript carbon copy of an essay considering the role the National Christian Council
  - Protest of Ransomed Americans, May 1923. Typescript carbon copy transcribed from the China Press, of a speech written for Anne Alter Fearm at the Shaghai Town Hall
  - The Purpose of Life, 24 August 1934. Two typescript carbon copies of CLB's meditation
  - The Rise and Development of Protestant Missions in China, 4 October 1939. Typescript carbon copy
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 15 April 1945. See Chapei Civil Assembly Speeches
  - Sermons. Miscellaneous sermons and fragments. Typescripts and carbon copies
  - Shanghai American School. See also Autobiographical writings, Shanghai American School History
    - A Brief Chronology, June 1936. Two typescript carbon copies
    - Commencement Address, Shanghai American School, 1925. Typescript
    - The Growth of an Idea, n.d. Typescript carbon copy
    - Notes for the History and Reunion Proposal, n.d. Typescripts
  - Statement of Faith, 7 May 1906. Original typescript and carbon copy of the address given under examination for ordination. See also Autobiographical writings, This I Believe for explanatory notes
  - Trained, Tried, True, 23 June 1924. Original typescript and two carbon copies of a commencement address delivered at South China College
  - Union Church Sermons, 1918, 1922, and 1939. Handwritten and typescript notes for sermons
  - The Use of Subsidies, 17 February 1933. Original typescript and two carbon copies of a personal memorandum
  - We are the Pilgrims of Hope, 22 November 1945. Original typescript and carbon copy of a Thanksgiving Day address delivered at the Community Church of Shanghai
  - What is the Present Status of the Protestant Enterprise in China? ca. 1937. Typescript carbon copy
  - What is Truth? ca. 1930. Original typescript and carbon copy of his personal meditation
  - YMCA Annual Reports 1908-1910. Two original typescripts and a carbon copy of the 1910 report
- SUBJECT FILE, 1901-1966. (Box 4-6)
  Charts, graphs, correspondence, notes, periodicals, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - American Association of China, Shanghai
  - Boynton, Leila Dozier - Correspondence
  - Cemetary lists
    - Beijing
    - Shanghai
    - Tientsin
  - Chinese-American Institute of Cultural Relations, Shanghai
  - Community Church of Shanghai
    - General
    - Announcements
    - Annual reports and financial statements
    - Governing Board
    - Membership, 1938
    - Minutes
    - Parish bulletin
    - Parish scope
    - Women's Auxiliary
  - Consuls in China, 1845-1935
  - Cross, Laura - Poetry
  - Education
  - Evacuation of China, 1948
  - Floods
  - Hallock, Henry Galloway C.
  - Hensley, Reverend and Mrs. C. Marvin
  - Koreans in Shanghai
  - Maps. Correspondence regarding the collecting of, Mattox, Dr. E.L.
  - Miao, Chester S. See also Post World War II, Correspondence, American Consulate
  - Minute Man, 1922
  - Missionaries in China, ca. 1910 (Box 5)
    - Charts, diagrams
    - Correspondence
    - The Future of Christian Missions in China. Memorandum of informal discussions by a group of missionaries
    - Lists. See also NOTEBOOKS
      - Miscellaneous
      - General
      - Americans in Shanghai, 19 December 1945
      - Chapei Civil Assembly Center
      - Gibbon's Catalogue's Monthly Supplement, 1905-1903
      - Revisions
  - Moslems in China, N.E.Z. Pickens
  - National Christian Council of China, Shanghai
  - North China American, 1935
  - Post World War II
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous and fragments
      - American Consulate
      - Boynton, Edmund
      - Cross, Rowland M.
      - Decker, Dr. J.W.
      - Fairlield, Wynn G.
      - McKenna, James (re: repatriation)
      - Sakamoto, James G. (re: repatriation)
      - Wegener, R. (re: repatriation)
    - Shanghai - Celebrations, invitations
    - U.S. Forces, Shanghai, 1946 - Telephone directory
  - Religious pamphlets (Box 6)
  - Robertson, Clarence H. Robbie
  - Shanghai Municipal Orchestra
  - Thanksgiving Services, Holy Trinity Cathedral, Shanghai
  - United Board of Christian Colleges, New York
    - General
    - Annual reports
    - New Horizons
  - United Church Board for World Missions Newsletter
  - Wheaton Alumni Quarterly, Summer 1964
  - Women's Groups, Shanghai
  - YMCA. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, YMCA Annual Reports
- CHAPEI CIVIL ASSEMBLY CENTER, 1943-1945. (Box 6)
  Correspondence, minutes, periodicals, service prayers, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Chapei speeches, and nominating speech for H.F. Kay; SUBJECT FILE, Missionaries, Chapei, and Miao, Chester S.; NOTEBOOKS
  - Assembly Times, 1943-1945 (Box 6)
  - Bulletin, American Baptist Foreign Missionary Society
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous
    - Boynton, Edmund C.
    - Damsgaard, Alexis and Dorothy
    - Dozier, Mary Boynton (Mrs. Barton)
    - Morgan, Edith
    - Wechsler, Rudolf
    - Woodward, Peggy Anddibark
  - Examinations held by the University of Cambridge Local Examinations Syndicate, 1944 and 1945
  - Minute book of Protestant Church (transcribed)
  - Notes
  - Service prayers during internment
  - Transcripts of small notebooks. See NOTEBOOKS for original copies
- SHANGHAI AMERICAN SCHOOL, 1912-1963. (Box 7)
  Correspondence, minutes, notes, periodicals, prospecti, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Shanghai American School; NOTEBOOKS, student enrollment lists and school newspaper
  - Alumni (Box 7)
  - Construction
  - Correspondence
  - Curriculum
  - Enrollment lists. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Westbrook, Louise and Hart; NOTEBOOKS
    - General
    - Prior to CLB's administration
    - 1912-1941
  - Financial records
  - History - Correspondence
    - General
    - Anderson, Colena
    - Bartlett, Willard W.
    - Merwin, Wallace
  - Minutes
  - Notes
  - Origins and dedication
  - Post war reopening
  - Prospecti and other printed matter
  - Reunion, Class of 1936
  - Shanghai American, 1935-1937
  - Status reports
- NOTEBOOKS AND OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1910-1945. (Box 8-9)
  Address books, Chapei camp notes, guest books, lists of missionaries and students, personal notes
  - 20 notebooks compiled by CLB and three oversize folders (Box 8-9)
- PHOTOGRAPHS. (Box 10.A-V)
  - 30 prints depicting Charles Luther Boynton and his wife, mostly in Shanghai, China, with friends and colleagues of the National Christian Council of China, the China Continuation Committee, the Chinese YMCA, the Shanghai American School, the China Amsterdam Youth Conference Delegation, the American Women's Club, the Phi Beta Kappa Officers' Association, the H.S.S. Galveston sailors, and the U.S. Army. Includes one print of Chiang Kai-shek and Madame Chiang Kai-shek, as well as many other Chinese acquaintances, 1916-1941 (Folder A)
  - 13 prints depicting Peking, 1920; Shanghai, 1939-1940; Kuling, 1909; and 3 negatives of a refugee camp after a typhoon, 6 July 1939 (Folder B)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 10-11)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu